Guide to the Chai Feldblum papers
Feldblum, Chai papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Chai Feldblum papers, 1975-1997
7697
19.2 cubic feet
Feldblum, Chai
Printed material, manuscripts, and videocassettes.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Materials of Professor Chai Feldblum relating to the effort by the Campaign for Military Service to assist President Clinton in his stated desire to lift the ban on gay service members. These materials include all documents used to lobby Congress and raise public awareness in 1993, as well as internal documents detailing efforts to propose alternatives to the Don't Ask Don't Tell policy. Also, files regarding the Employment Non-Discrimination Act (ENDA).
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor Chai Feldblum was the Legal Director for the Campaign for Military Service (CMS).
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Materials of Professor Chai Feldblum relating to the effort by the Campaign for Military Service to assist President Clinton in his stated desire to lift the ban on gay service members. These materials include all documents used to lobby Congress and raise public awareness in 1993, as well as internal documents detailing efforts to propose alternatives to the Don't Ask Don't Tell policy.
Also, files regarding the Employment Non-Discrimination Act (ENDA).
SUBJECTS
Names:
Feldblum, Chai.; Campaign for Military Service.
Subjects:
ENDA; United States--Armed Forces--Gays--Government policy.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access for research purposes only.
One folder of correspondence has been RESTRICTED until 2019. This folder is temporarily stored in the Accession File.
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
Where possible, original folder headings have been retained. Folders labeled "Miscellaneous" contain information papers, comments by Navy officers, retired officials and veterans, various background papers, and other ban-related miscellany.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Briefing Notebooks
Boxes 1-2
Series II. Congressional Record Project
Boxes 2-3
Series III. Research Files
Boxes 3-15, 19-20
Series IV. CMS Organizational Materials
Box 15
Series V. Videos
Box 16
Series VI. Employment Non-Discrimination Act (ENDA)
Boxes 17-22
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Briefing Notebooks
  - Campaign for Military Service- Potential Witnesses (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - History (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Combat Exclusion (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
  - Campaign for Military Service Congressional Briefing Book (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Support Documents: Active Duty: Quality-of-Life Benefits (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Editorials- model articles, op-eds, etc. (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
  - Senate Supporters (Box 1, Folder 9-10)
  - Background Information on Eliminating Discrimination on the Basis of Sexual Orientation in the Armed Forces (Box 1, Folder 11-13)
  - International Briefing Book (Box 1, Folder 14-15)
  - Briefing book: Gays in the Military (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - House Hearing Briefing Book (Box 1, Folder 17-19)
  - Federal Legislation Clinic (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Campaign for Military Service binder (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - House Briefing Book (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
  - Notebook of miscellaneous reports/information (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
  - Jonathan Bowie notebook (?) (Box 2, Folder 7-9)
  - Campaign for Military Service (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Background Materials in Support of Lifting the Ban on Gay Men and Lesbians in the Military- Congressional Briefing Book (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Briefing notebook (Box 2, Folder 12-13)
  - History- legal- Unit Cohesion (Box 2, Folder 14-16)
  - "Original Briefing Book Prior to Final Revisions", first version (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Briefing Book- Final Revised Copy #1 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Series II. Congressional Record Project
  - Commentaries, news articles, letters to the editors, Part I (Box 2, Folder 19-20)
  - Commentaries, news articles, letters to the editors, Part II (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
  - Commentaries, news articles, letters to the editors, Part III (Box 3, Folder 3-4)
  - Selected Materials from Day-to-Day Lobbying Activities (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
  - Final Report and Recommendations by FEMA, Security Practices Board of Review (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Relevant Pages from House and Senate Committee Reports (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - A Comprehensive Proposal for Lifting the Ban on Gay, Lesbian, and Bisexual Service Members in the United States Military (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Proceedings and debates of the 104th Congress, 1st session (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - The Constitutional Invalidity of the Ban (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - The Ban: Before and After the '92 Election (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Agenda: April 14, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Sample Lobby Packets (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - The American Legion, June 1993, articles on Gays in the Military (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Campaign for Military Service Senate Hearings Press Kit (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Series III. Research Files
  - DOD Inspector General- Tailhook 91, Part 2 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - "A Comparative Survey and Analysis of Military Policies with Regard to Service by Gay Persons", by Frank Pond (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - "A Comparative Analysis of Military Policies with Regard to Gays and Lesbians", by Frank Pond (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - "Analysis of Professor Charles Moskos' Views on the Elimination of the Ban on Openly Gay Servicemembers", by Marc Wolinsky (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - "Pat Robertson and the Christian Coalition: Combating 'Stealth' Opponents and Last-Minute Attacks" (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Deal stuff (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - CMS: Plans; letters, etc. (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - CMS- personal (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - CMS research memos (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Memo to Clinton from Reno re: DOD Policy (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - White House (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Open statement (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Frank (Barney) compromise (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - CMS stationary, fax sheets (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Meinhold- response to Cpt. Markwell statement (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Meinhold v. US DOD (Tucker Act) (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Meinhold- opposition materials (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Meinhold decision (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Immigration and HIV (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Congressional Record (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Nunn legislation (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Meinhold- request for stay, G & R circuit order (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Meinhold- stuff (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Meinhold- decisions (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Medical power of attorney (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Meinhold pleadings (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Information regarding prisoners (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Armed services committee hearing on Unit Cohesion minutes (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Nunn testimony (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous background materials (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Congressman Michel's response to constituent concern over the ban (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Summary of homosexual expulsion policies for foreign militaries (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Armed Forces homosexuality policy statements (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous background papers (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Summary of main arguments against eliminating ban (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Neutral discussion of the ban and "advice" for the DOD (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Number of DOD military personnel separated due to homosexuality since 1971 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Sodomy law information (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Excerpt from the Uniform Code of Military Justice concerning sodomy (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Study analyzing behaviors of homosexual men seeking medical care in Los Angeles County (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Resources on converting from homosexuality to heterosexuality (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Arguments against homosexuality being inherent from a scientific basis (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Information on sexually transmitted diseases (not AIDS) in homosexuals (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Concerns over possible accidental transmission of AIDS (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Cost estimates of treating HIV/AIDS (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Reprint of the National Coalition of Gay Organizations' "Gay Rights Platform" (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Probably behavior in homosexuals based on requests in personal ads (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Historical discussions of "Buggery" and the British Navy (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Dr. Seuss spoof (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Codifying the DOD homosexual exclusion policy (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - "Leave for FDR" (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Amendments (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Nan's testimony (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - "Friendly Fire" draft, by Burr (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Witness list (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Lucian Truscott (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - News articles (Box 4, Folder 38-40)
  - Chandler Burr (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Testimonials from straight veterans (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Open statement (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Bibliographies (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Comprehensive proposal (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - News release folder (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - The Ban: Before and After the '92 Election (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Field visits to military bases by the Senate Armed Services Committee (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Agenda- April 14, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - CMS information folder (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - The Constitutional Invalidity of the Ban (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - CMS: Survey of 1004 Registered Voters (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Gays and Lesbians in the Military: Focus Group Transcripts, Tampa, FL (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Focus Group Transcripts, Dayton, OH (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Focus Group Transcripts, New Orleans (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Gays and Lesbians in the Military: Results of Focus Groups and a National Survey (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - CMS information packet draft (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Witness panel transcripts (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - CMS background material (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Booklet copies (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Endorsement Forms and Letters (Box 5, Folder 9-10)
  - Anti-ban petition (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Endorsement letters (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Endorsement materials/news articles (Box 5, Folder 13-14)
  - "Targeted Editorials" (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Humor (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Rational Basis (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - First Amendment (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Legal Analysis: Don't Ask, Don't Tell (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Rights of Association (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Editorials (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Sample Floor Statements (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Floor Statement background information (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Recent news articles (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Testimonials (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - News clippings (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - On-base clubs (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Right to Association (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Polls: Political Consequence of Supporting Gay Rights (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Polls: Equal Opportunity (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Powell/Harvard Commencement (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Compromise (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Allies/police/fire department personnel (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Editorials (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - General articles (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Heros (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - ROTC (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Southern Poverty Law Center (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - VFW (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Fun articles (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - "Scott" (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Heymann Memo (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - CMS letterhead (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Volunteer law students (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Volunteer lawyers (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Robert Bourguignon Sparer fellowship program (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Military freedom project (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - CMS: general/staff meeting (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Gay rights: military (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - CMS (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Deal (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - End Game (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Chai: From CMS (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Georgetown University related materials (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Rand summarized (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - #1 Overview of the Issue (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - #2 Exclusion Policy (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - #3 History of the Exclusion Policy (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - #4 Policy Rationale (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - #5 Civil Rights & Discrimination (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - #6 Legal Issues (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - #7 Health Issues (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - #8 Homosexuality + Armed Forces (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - #9 Recommendations (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - #10 Support (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Rand Report: Sexual Orientation and US Military Personnel Policy: Options and Assessment (Box 6, Folder 17-19)
  - Supporting organizations (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Religious endorsements (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Religion (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Religious organizations (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Add to Chron (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Opinion Polls (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Moskos (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - MLR articles (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Hawaii marriage case (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - DEOMI (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Confidential- Active Gay Military Personnel (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Current (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Zuniga (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Dixon Osbourne (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Psychology/choice (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Family Research Council (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Parris Island (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Judith Stiehm/Calvin Waller (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Col. John Ripley (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Stephen Leinen- "Gay Cops" (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Senate Hearings- March 31 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - ACLU (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Benecke (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - "Homosexuality and Biology" by Chandler Burr (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Bell and Weinberg book (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Berube materials (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Bashing (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Cost (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Greg Craig materials (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Congressional Record re: Gays in the Military (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Berube materials (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Mario Cooper (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Constitutionality Invalidity Test (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Contacts (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Crittendon Report (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Defense Readiness Council (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Discharges (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - DOD recommendation meeting authorizations (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Do's and Don't for SMS (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - DOD policy, etc. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - DOD Directive- administrative separation procedures (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Field visits (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - FOIA example (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Frank (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Ginsburg (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Georgetown Law Center- military recruiting (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Grass roots (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - HRCF (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Herbits/Seagram (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - History of military's ban (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Implementation (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Journal articles (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Kameny (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Kennedy Iskowitz (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Legislation (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Locker rooms (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - March on Washington (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - John McGuire/Meinhold (Moskos too) (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - CMS- media, etc. (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Military discharge upgrading (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Military Freedom Project (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Military viewpoint: pro-ban (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Military viewpoint: anti-ban (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Mundy/CMC (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - NAACP (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - News articles (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Newspaper articles- ban related (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Newspaper articles- non ban specific (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Nunn's 1/27/93 statement (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Stoddard, Moskos- Larry King (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Articles/press (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - NGLTF fact sheets (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - NLGLA (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Gay-related news (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Opinion polls (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Opposition reports (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - News articles (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Field Visits to Military Bases by the Senate Armed Services Committee (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - DOD Authorization Bill- Senate Committee Report (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Doe v. Aspin Bowie letter (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Benecke CMS/SLDN (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Steffan (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - News materials (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Opposition/military panel senate hearings (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Korb (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Proposed Questions in Response to Testimony of Charles Moskos (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Non-discrimination document proposal (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - American Psychiatric Association (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Sodomy (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Phillips v. Aspin (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Cause of Homosexuality (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Miscellaneous documents, reports, papers (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - CMS papers (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Endgame (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Standard of Review (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Correspondence re: Gay Civil Rights Bill (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - Option papers (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Meinhold analysis (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - Meinhold (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Clinton letter (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous reports/news articles (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Promiscuity (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Race (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Congressional Record (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Current (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Comics (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Jarrett (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Cover letters (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Bad polls: WV, LA, FL (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Faxes (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Gregor (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Changing attitudes (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Marriage in Hawaii (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Public Health Service (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - House Hearings Q and A (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - House Hearings general (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Senate Hearing 3/29/93 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Weise (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Gregory Hesek (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Striedinger, Seattle Police Guild (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Brig Gen. Jim Hutchens (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - MCPO Chuck Jackson (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Wells-Petry: Exclusion (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Constitution articles (Box 8, Folder 26-27)
  - Miscellaneous articles (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Charles Moskos: international response (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Saltzburg (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Legal Panel: Dale- Q's and statement (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Saltzburg- Q's (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Gregor (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - International News- general (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Research: Australia (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Research: Canada (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Research: France (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Research: NATO (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Research: Netherlands (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Research: Israel (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Research: Sweden (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Research: Greece, Portugal, Italy, Spain (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - International (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Henderson book: Cohesion (Box 8, Folder 44-46)
  - Henderson book (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Hearings (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Charles Dale/legal panel (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Follow-up to March hearings (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Gregory Herek (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Segal (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Constitutional Law witnesses (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Q & A March (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Hearings- March- Background (Box 9, Folder 3-4)
  - Homosexuality + Biology (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Answers to Senator Nunn's Questions (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Questions and Answers (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Homosexuals in the Military- issues (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - CMS- Draft proposal materials, notes (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Agenda- April 14, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous documents (Box 9, Folder 11-12)
  - CMS information packets (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Statements and notes (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Analysis of Prof. Charles Moskos' View on the Elimination of the Ban on Openly Gay Servicemembers (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous documents, correspondence, reports (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Background Information on Eliminating Discrimination on the Basis of Sexual Orientation in the Armed Forces (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - CRS report on "Homosexuals and US Military Personnel Policy" (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - FEMA report (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Scott Foster (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - UCMJ: CRS (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous documents (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - "Homosexuals and US Military Personnel Policy: Policy Options and Assessment- An Interim Report" (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - DOD Task Force (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Herbits materials (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Executive Order (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - CMS Legislative Division (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Policy statements/fact sheets (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous documents (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - "Homosexuals in the Military: Policies and Practices of Foreign Countries" (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - "Nonconforming Sexual Orientations and Military Suitability" (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - "Pre-service Adjustment of Homosexual and Heterosexual Military Accessions: Implications for Security Clearance Suitability" (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - "Defense Force Management: DOD's Policy on Homosexuality" (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Miscellaneous statements (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Legislative (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Personal case histories information (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Senate Hearing materials (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Testimonies and statements (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Senate Hearing transcripts (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Civil rights (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - "A Comparative Survey and Analysis of Military Policies with Regard to Service by Gay Persons" (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous issue-related papers (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Hearing rebuttals (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - History (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Press (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - "Homosexuals in the Military: Policies and Practices of Foreign Countries" (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - "Homosexual Security Issue" paper (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - News releases/statements (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - "A Retired Pastor Breaks His Silence: Coming to Grips with Homosexuality" by Lowell Zechial (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - "Homosexuality, Morality, and Equality", remarks prepared for a forum at Mary Washington College by Donald Rallis (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Steffan declarations (Box 10, Folder 16-18)
  - Trial documents (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous trial-related documents (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Steffan (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Administrative Discharge Board Proceedings in the Case of Sgt. J. Elzie (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Meinhold (Box 10, Folder 23-24)
  - Thorne (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Trial transcripts/summaries (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Trial transcripts/summaries/general documents (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence to Chai Feldblum, from "Michelle" (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Lawyers- non DC (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Document library (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Frank Pond chronology (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Legal team (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Quotes (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Transcripts (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - HIV (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Article- outline & timeline (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - U.S.C. 2302 (1993): Prohibited Personnel Practices (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - F.P.M Chapter 752 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - F.P.M. Chapter 731 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Supporting case law (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Defensibility of the New Policy (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Nan Hunter's 3/31/93 Senate testimony (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Lesbian/gay civil rights roundtable (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Military ban- ACLU (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Press clippings (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Dahl v. Secretary of US Navy (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Doe v. Aspin (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Blaesing (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Steffan v. Aspin (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Elzie v. Aspin (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Meinhold decision (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Meinhold (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Meinhold v. DOD (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Selland v. Aspin (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - DOJ (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Gay/Lesbian Task Force Domestic Partnership Manual (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - AIDS advisory committee (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Harvard Law- Gay/Lesbian Alumni Committee (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Harvard Law School Association (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Harvard Law School Association- Gay/Lesbian & Bisexual Alumni Committee (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Memos to administration (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Messages & miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - News articles (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - "Nudge" folder (?) (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - Equality Foundation v. Cincinnati (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - Gay Rights cases (Box 11, Folder 40)